<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Monkey Poo]]></title>
  <link href="http://socme.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://socme.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-11T18:09:15+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://socme.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Utilities for Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/utilities-for-windows/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T13:57:13+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/utilities-for-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/windowsmodern.png" width="100" height="100">
Here&rsquo;s a few Windows programs I find indispensable.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First these are my basic disc/ISO tools.</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left;">  </th>
<th style="text-align:left;">  </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> ISO2Disc </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="http://www.top-password.com/iso2disc.html">http://www.top-password.com/iso2disc.html</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> This is the best burner I&rsquo;ve found. It burns bootable ISO&rsquo;s to both CD/DVDs and USB flash drives (UFD). Excellent for making bootable <strong>Windows Installation</strong> USB drives. </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <br> </td>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> WinMD5 </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="http://winmd5.com/">http://winmd5.com/</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Nice simple MD5 calculator and checker.  No installation is required, just run the exe file. </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <br> </td>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> InfraRecorder</td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="http://infrarecorder.org/">http://infrarecorder.org/</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> A useful CD/DVD burner with some neat features ie. it can report which formats the drive can read and write. </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <br> </td>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> ImageUSB </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="http://www.osforensics.com/tools/write-usb-images.html">http://www.osforensics.com/tools/write-usb-images.html</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> A useful tool with the ability to format or zero a USB drive or to create an ISO from a USB drive. </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <br> </td>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> EasyBCD </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="https://neosmart.net/EasyBCD/">https://neosmart.net/EasyBCD/</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> For setting up multi boot systems from Windows. Is of limited use now as Windows on a <strong>UEFI</strong> PC can&rsquo;t boot linux, see the following for an explanation (post #4). </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="https://neosmart.net/forums/threads/terry60-windows-8-basic-problem-considerations.13514/#post-82798">https://neosmart.net/forums/threads/terry60-windows-8-basic-problem-considerations.13514/#post-82798</a> </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p><br>
For the Raspberry Pi I use these:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left;">  </th>
<th style="text-align:left;">  </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> PuTTY </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="http://www.putty.org/">http://www.putty.org/</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> PuTTY is an SSH and telnet client. Connect and control the Pi from another computer </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <br> </td>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Auremo </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <a href="http://auremo.codeplex.com/">http://auremo.codeplex.com/</a> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">  </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Auremo is a graphical client for the Music Player Daemon (MPD). Control the Pi&rsquo;s music player from a remote computer, makes adding streams and playlists a breeze </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Swift Seen]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/05/06/swift-seen/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-06T13:10:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/05/06/swift-seen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/swift160x100.jpg" width="160" height="90"></p>

<p>A Swift shows up and examines the nesting site above my flat.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>This is the first Swift I&rsquo;ve seen this year. For years now a pair have been nesting in the eaves above my flat, I get great views of these beautiful birds.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been three days now and I haven&rsquo;t seen it or any others since!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My New Computer]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/04/30/my-new-computer/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-30T13:16:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/04/30/my-new-computer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/fractaldesigncase.jpeg" width="120" height="180"></p>

<p>A long time coming but now built and running both Windows 7 for gaming and openSUSE for every thing else.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Had a lot of fun putting this box together. As always quietness is a priority for me and I&rsquo;m pleased to say this is a very quiet machine.</p>

<p>There have been many improvements in hardware since I built my last computer a few years ago. At last liquid cooling is affordable, this is a much quieter option than the stock CPU cooler. Also modern power supplies and graphics cards don&rsquo;t spin their fans until they&rsquo;re needed, making a noticeable reduction in noise levels. Rumbling Hard Disk Drives are replaced by silent Solid State Drives. Put all this in a case fitted with dense, sound-absorbing material and you have a whisper quiet computer. Just what I need.</p>

<p>With just one SSD fitted, Windows 7 was installed from a USB drive. Fast and painless. After testing the system using the utilities that came with the hardware. A second smaller SSD was fitted and openSUSE Linux was installed. As Windows cant boot a second drive with the newer UEFI bios the boot order must be changed to the second SSD letting Linux chain load Windows.</p>

<p>So now I enjoy fast start ups, playing games at high graphic settings, optical audio out, responsive desktops and all that &hellip; nice!</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left;"> Components     </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> :              </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> CPU            </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> AMD FX-8 8350  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> MOBO           </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> ASUS SABERTOOTH 990FX R2.0  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> GPU            </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> ASUS GTX 960 STRIX </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> RAM            </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> KINGSTON HyperX Fury 16GB (2X8GB) 1866MHz DDR3  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> SSD            </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> CRUCIAL MX100 512GB Windows 7 installed  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> SSD            </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> SANDISK 128GB openSUSE 13.2 installed  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> PSU            </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> XFX XXX EDITION PSU 850 WATT  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> COOLER         </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> NZXT KRAKEN X41  </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> CASE           </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> FRACTAL DESIGN R5 Black  </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Roguelike Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/05/a-new-roguelike-game/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-05T12:02:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/05/a-new-roguelike-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Crawl - a Roguelike dungeon exploration game for Linux and Windows.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/">Dungeon Crawl: Stone Soup</a> is a fun game in the grand tradition of games like Rogue, Hack, and Moria. Your objective is to travel deep into a subterranean cave complex and retrieve the Orb of Zot, which is guarded by many horrible and hideous creatures.</p>

<p>I first played <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rogue_%28video_game%29">Rogue</a> on a Commodore 16 in the mid 80&rsquo;s and loved it, in fact it wasn&rsquo;t long before the whole family was addicted. Over the years I&rsquo;ve played many versions of the original, this is one of the best.</p>

<h4><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike">Roguelike Games</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike"><img src="http://socme.github.io/images/epyxrogue.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolution a Game for Mobiles]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/04/utopia-plus-plus/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-04T11:27:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/04/utopia-plus-plus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Evolution: Battle for Utopia, gets a thumbs up.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://evo.my.com/en/#0">Evolution: Battle for Utopia</a> from my.com is an action, RPG with strategy elements. The action sections are fast and furious battles against a variety of NPC opponents. You&rsquo;ll need to manage your resources wisely especially if your playing for free. Unless you spend money on this game be prepared for slow progress. There is some PVP but it&rsquo;s not something I&rsquo;m very fond of so haven&rsquo;t tried it as yet.</p>

<p>Great graphics, fun game-play, a nice variety of side-games and cool weapons this game has a lot going for it. Been playing this free for two or three weeks now and still coming back for more, so it can&rsquo;t be too bad.</p>

<h4><a href="http://evo.my.com/en/#0">Evolution: Battle for Utopia</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://evo.my.com/en/#0"><img src="http://socme.github.io/images/utopia.png"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C9 an Action RPG]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/01/19/c9-an-action-rpg/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-19T12:56:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/01/19/c9-an-action-rpg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Continent of the Ninth Seal from Webzen is a very playable action rpg.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The game play is pretty hectic with lots of combo moves and big bosses. The animation is good, the graphics are OK and it runs smoothly on my oldish computer. Pleasantly surprised.</p>

<p>All those combos strain my memory, no bad thing really as I can use the mental exercise. Quick reactions and good timing are also important, more stuff I need to practice.</p>

<h4><a href="http://c9.webzen.com/main">C9</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://c9.webzen.com/main"><img src="http://socme.github.io/images/C9.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Way to Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/01/09/way-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-09T11:10:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/01/09/way-to-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well I&rsquo;ve been mucking about with this blogging system for awhile now so it&rsquo;s time to decide which way to go, I&rsquo;m liking it to find out why &hellip;</p>

<!--more-->


<p>As a Linux user I found the creation of github pages has a familiar work flow, edit, local preview, git commit/push and we&rsquo;re done. Using the Atom editor to create the markdown content then using the built in preview feature helps speed up the creation of pages. Octopress provides a local preview server so we can see the final result before committing and pushing to the web via the command line.</p>

<p>As a Windows user github has the usual installer which provides a GUI and console allowing access to your github account from the desktop. Unfortunately Octopress doesn&rsquo;t support Windows, use Jenkyll it works, overall using Windows is somewhat awkward. As most of my projects are Linux based (Windows is my gaming OS) I&rsquo;m not so concerned that Windows is less supported than I would like.</p>

<p>So I&rsquo;m happy to continue with GitHub Pages and Octopress, for the amount of posting I do (very little) it seems a natural choice. The future might see the Diaspora project coming to maturity if so that could be the way to go, for now though I&rsquo;m happy staying here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hair Cutting for Growth?]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/hair-cutting-for-growth/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T15:21:17+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/22/hair-cutting-for-growth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This question has obvious relevance to me, as after 33 sessions of radiotherapy I had a goodly amount of hair loss from the top of my head. Now four weeks after the treatment I&rsquo;m getting some growth and hair seems to be returning.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>When the question of cutting hair to stimulate growth came up recently there was a divergence of opinion. So after a bit of web research it turns out that cutting has <strong>NO</strong> effect on hair growth. See below for links to more information.</p>

<hr />

<p><br />
<a href="http://www.zapahair.com/pages/article_02.html"><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/popeye.png"></a></p>

<p>This <a href="http://www.zapahair.com/pages/article_02.html" title="">interesting article</a> tells in some detail why cutting hair has no effect on hair grow.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaving#Myths">Shaving Myths</a> on Wikipedia also explains how shaving may give the impression of stimulating hair growth.</p>

<p>An interesting <a href="http://www.nhs.uk/Tools/Pages/hair-loss-myths.aspx">Myth Buster</a> from the NHS.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Back to Gaming]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/getting-back-to-gaming/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-17T15:37:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/getting-back-to-gaming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Getting back to gaming after brain surgery has been a bit weird.</p>

<p>Obviously for the first week or two I felt rubbish and had no interest in gaming at all but it wasn&rsquo;t long before I was well enough to get bored. The only problem was I couldn&rsquo;t concentrate for more than just a few minutes at a time. So I started playing text based browser games, I&rsquo;m a fan of these anyway so no great hardship there. Using the mouse and keyboard turned out to be good therapy and was helping me get my coordination back, so win win.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Can&rsquo;t remember which client based game I tried first, probably <a href="http://world.needforspeed.com/">Need for Speed</a>. Well that just made me feel sea sick and I haven&rsquo;t been able to play it since, a pity really because I did play it regularly. I went on to downloaded quite few others and enjoyed <a href="http://www.trionworlds.com/defiance/en/">Defiance</a> and <a href="http://www.firefallthegame.com/features">Firefall</a> (see below). I got on best with Defiance, even though it&rsquo;s a hectic game I could play at my own pace.</p>

<p>So now it&rsquo;s been five months since surgery and I&rsquo;ve just finished two months of Radiotherapy. Mainly I play browser games still (see below for details) but I&rsquo;ve just rediscovered <a href="https://warframe.com/">War Frame</a>, I played it lots last year. It&rsquo;s another hectic combat game and I can&rsquo;t play it for more than an hour or so, but it&rsquo;s changed enough over the past year to feel fresh again. So that&rsquo;s that, I&rsquo;ll be talking more about the games I come across in future posts.</p>

<h2>The Browser Games</h2>

<h4><a href="http://www.godwars.us">Godwars</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://www.godwars.us"><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/godwars.png" width="160" height="100"></a>
The fantasy universe of Godwars is an interesting and addictive dungeon crawler with bells on. A new game, not a year old yet, this one has me coming back again and again. The game is still in development, and has a lot of potential that&rsquo;s not been realized yet. Starting out is a bit confusing but once you&rsquo;ve created your prophet (main character) your quickly into the dimensions (dungeons) and ready to start bashing monsters. Plenty of help in their Wiki, but once you get started it&rsquo;s a pretty straight forward game so don&rsquo;t worry if you get stuck at first.</p>

<h4><a href="http://www.sryth.com/">Sryth</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://www.sryth.com/"><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/sryth.gif" width="160" height="100"></a>
Sryth is a single-player fantasy RPG, a text based browser game. In Sryth, the game&rsquo;s events, adventures, and story-lines revolve around you the main character. You&rsquo;ll need to pay $20 for the years subscription, the game can be played for free but will soon grind to a halt without that subscription. I like the games relaxed game play and absorbing story line, it&rsquo;s turn based so smoke breaks can be taken when ever there&rsquo;s a need. With plenty to explore and lots of loot you might have to buy a house to keep it in &hellip; real money! It should keep me going for awhile, the whole year? well we&rsquo;ll see.</p>

<h4><a href="http://hackandcast.com">Hack and Cast</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://hackandcast.com"><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/HaC.png" width="160" height="100"></a>
Hack and Cast hosts monthly competitions, rewarding players with cash and in-game currency. Enter into their monthly Beast Hunt competition, in which competing HAC fighters slay as many beasts as possible to win the competition.</p>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t been playing this one long, it&rsquo;s quite slow to get started but the friendly but small user base can be generous and give you a help up. The game is in constant development and has changed quite a bit lately, for the better I would say. How long it takes before you have a chance in the competitions depends on the time you have, and the dollars you spend.</p>

<h2>The Client Games</h2>

<h4><a href="http://www.trionworlds.com/defiance/en/">Defiance</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://www.trionworlds.com/defiance/en/"><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/defiance160x100.png" width="160" height="100"></a>
A pretty hectic 3rd person shooter with lots of guns. My favorite at the moment even though my computer struggles to keep up. The pve events are much like rifts in Rift and are a lot of fun. Made in collaboration with the tv series, which I didn&rsquo;t like so much. It&rsquo;s now free to play.</p>

<h4><a href="http://www.firefallthegame.com/">Firefall</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://www.firefallthegame.com/"><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/firefall160x100.png" width="160" height="100"></a>
An enjoyable game that runs well on my oldish computer. Lots of shooting with an important crafting element makes for a quite varied game. New updates have occurred since I played it last, might be worth another look. Stopped playing this in favor of Defiance, see above.</p>

<h4><a href="https://warframe.com/">War Frame</a></h4>

<p><a href="https://warframe.com/"><img src="http://socme.github.io/images/warframe.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.spaceinvaders.net/">Space Invaders</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kingfisher Spotted]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/16/kingfisher-spotted/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-16T16:27:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/16/kingfisher-spotted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Caught the turquoise flash of a Kingfisher today.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://www.rspb.org.uk/discoverandenjoynature/discoverandlearn/birdguide/name/k/kingfisher/index.aspx?utm_source=bing&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Endangered%20Birds&utm_term=kingfisher"><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/kingfisher.jpg"></a></p>

<p>I was lucky enough to see a Kingfisher flying up the river today, they don&rsquo;t hang about though so it was only a glimpse really. That&rsquo;s the second I&rsquo;ve seen in the village recently, haven&rsquo;t seen one here for years.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Left to My Own Devices]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/16/left-to-my-own-devices/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-16T15:55:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/16/left-to-my-own-devices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/tegra160x100.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Recently I purchased a new mobile phone and a 7&#8221; tablet. They&rsquo;ve both been excellent and I wouldn&rsquo;t be without them.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><br />
<br /></p>

<p><a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/os/devices/#zte_openc"><img class="right" src="http://socme.github.io/images/zte-openc.png"></a>
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/os/devices/#zte_openc">ZTE Open C Mobile Phone</a></p>

<p>My new phone is from ZTE but more interesting is it&rsquo;s Firefox OS which is an alternative to Android etc. It&rsquo;s web centric components should make it easier for me to write apps for, we&rsquo;ll see. This model is a nice and small 4&#8221;, liking it!
<br />
<br /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.nvidia.co.uk/object/advent-vega-tegra-note-7-tablet-uk.html">Advent Vega Tegra Note 7 Tablet</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.nvidia.co.uk/object/advent-vega-tegra-note-7-tablet-uk.html"><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/advent-vega-tegra-note7.png"></a></p>

<p>I needed something to take with me on my recent visit to hospital. The Tegra Note 7 was cheap in the sales and proved to be a gem. Great for games and does all those things it should plus a stylus. Good stuff.</p>

<p>This is my first tablet, and its been a lot fun finding my way around it. A friend kindly lent me their iPod for a few days. I  found its 10&#8221; screen to be to big to be comfortably mobile, also not a fan of Apples products in general. So, I find this 7&#8221; size to be much easier to handle and the more rectangular screen to be more natural to view. Thumbs up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[That's a Raspberry Pi]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/thats-a-raspberry-pi/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T15:41:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/thats-a-raspberry-pi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://socme.github.io/images/Raspberry-Pi-display.jpg" width="160" height="100">The new <a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/products/model-b-plus/">Raspberry Pi B+</a> has been around for a while and now a <a href="http://www.adafruit.com/products/1601">touch screen</a> is available that looks pretty neat.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><br>
<br>
I still use my original model B every day as a music player, playing streams from the web. Also I use it regularly to play a couple of text based browser games that I indulge in. On the more serious side I have nodejs installed with an <a href="http://actionherojs.com/">actionhero</a> server up and running.</p>

<p>This 2.8 inch touch screen is from <a href="http://www.adafruit.com/products/1601">Adafruit</a>. Other manufactures and sizes are out there (<a href="https://duckduckgo.com/">duck duck go</a> is your friend).</p>

<p><img src="http://socme.github.io/images/Raspberry-Pi-display.jpg" alt="Pi" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World: A New Beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/14/hello-world-a-new-beginning/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-14T22:33:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2014/12/14/hello-world-a-new-beginning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Here we go again with a new project.</h4>

<!--more-->


<p>It looks like GitHub Pages and Octopress might be just the thing. I&rsquo;m giving it a go, so fingers crossed I&rsquo;ll be posting again.</p>

<p>Cool so far, found the install quite straight forward not for everyone though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
