<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gaming | Monkey Poo]]></title>
  <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/categories/gaming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://socme.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-07T12:03:04+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://socme.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/06/07/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-07T10:08:22+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/06/07/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100">
Having played it for a few weeks I can truly say this is a great game.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I was fortunate to get this game free with my new graphics card, normally it sells for around £50. The optimized settings for my Nvidia 960 GTX worked well, the resulting graphics quality is amazing.</p>

<p>The game is a single player RPG that follows an entertaining and well crafted story line, with plenty of sub-stories to explore. This post isn&rsquo;t intended to be a review, just my general first impressions of the game.</p>

<p>So, the animation is the best, loving the horse. The speech is excellent, especially in the cut scenes which are many and very well crafted. The combat system is intuitive. With only quick and heavy attacks with swords, fighting seems too simple at first but with special Witcher powers and throw-able bombs and later a crossbow combat gets as good as the rest of the game.</p>

<h4><a href="http://www.thewitcher.com">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://www.thewitcher.com"><img src="/images/witcher-monsterhunter.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Roguelike Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/05/a-new-roguelike-game/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-05T12:02:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/05/a-new-roguelike-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Crawl - a Roguelike dungeon exploration game for Linux and Windows.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://crawl.develz.org/wordpress/">Dungeon Crawl: Stone Soup</a> is a fun game in the grand tradition of games like Rogue, Hack, and Moria. Your objective is to travel deep into a subterranean cave complex and retrieve the Orb of Zot, which is guarded by many horrible and hideous creatures.</p>

<p>I first played <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rogue_%28video_game%29">Rogue</a> on a Commodore 16 in the mid 80&rsquo;s and loved it, in fact it wasn&rsquo;t long before the whole family was addicted. Over the years I&rsquo;ve played many versions of the original, this is one of the best.</p>

<h4><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike">Roguelike Games</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike"><img src="/images/epyxrogue.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolution a Game for Mobiles]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/04/utopia-plus-plus/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-04T11:27:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/02/04/utopia-plus-plus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Evolution: Battle for Utopia, gets a thumbs up.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://evo.my.com/en/#0">Evolution: Battle for Utopia</a> from my.com is an action, RPG with strategy elements. The action sections are fast and furious battles against a variety of NPC opponents. You&rsquo;ll need to manage your resources wisely especially if your playing for free. Unless you spend money on this game be prepared for slow progress. There is some PVP but it&rsquo;s not something I&rsquo;m very fond of so haven&rsquo;t tried it as yet.</p>

<p>Great graphics, fun game-play, a nice variety of side-games and cool weapons this game has a lot going for it. Been playing this free for two or three weeks now and still coming back for more, so it can&rsquo;t be too bad.</p>

<h4><a href="http://evo.my.com/en/#0">Evolution: Battle for Utopia</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://evo.my.com/en/#0"><img src="/images/utopia.png"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C9 an Action RPG]]></title>
    <link href="http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/01/19/c9-an-action-rpg/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-19T12:56:32+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://socme.github.io/blog/2015/01/19/c9-an-action-rpg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/spaceinvader.png" width="160" height="100"></p>

<p>Continent of the Ninth Seal from Webzen is a very playable action rpg.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The game play is pretty hectic with lots of combo moves and big bosses. The animation is good, the graphics are OK and it runs smoothly on my oldish computer. Pleasantly surprised.</p>

<p>All those combos strain my memory, no bad thing really as I can use the mental exercise. Quick reactions and good timing are also important, more stuff I need to practice.</p>

<h4><a href="http://c9.webzen.com/main">C9</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://c9.webzen.com/main"><img src="/images/C9.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
